Guide to the John Southworth papers, 1817-1921
Southworth, John papers, 1817-1921
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
John Southworth papers, 1817-1921.
3919
John Southworth, 1796-1877.
1.9 cubic ft.
Land deeds, mortgages, bonds, correspondence, ledgers, survey bills, lists of leases and purchases, letters patent, stock certificate books, checkbook, diary.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Financial records relating to land holdings, sales and leases by John Southworth in New York, Wisconsin, Michigan, Pennsylvania, Iowa, and Indiana.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
John Southworth moved from Herkimer County, New York to Dryden, Tompkins County, New York with his father, Thomas Southworth, in 1806. He became a large landholder and one of the wealthiest men in Tompkins County.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes land deeds from New York, Wisconsin, Michigan, Pennsylvania, Iowa, and Indiana; mortgages and bonds; letters patent; bank-related correspondence; legal correspondence; ledger sheets; survey bills; lists of leases and purchases; stock certificate books; checkbook; and diary.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Southworth, John, 1796-1877.; Southworth, Thomas.
Subjects:
Real property, Exchange of.
Form and Genre Terms:
Deeds.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Financial Records
  - Tompkins County land deeds, 1820-1888 (Box 1)
  - Tompkins County bonds, 1820-1876 (Box 2)
  - Tompkins County mortgages, 1817-1893 (Box 2)
  - Quit-claim deeds: Tompkins and Niagara Counties, New York; Marquette County, Wisconsin; Michigan, 1826-1880 (Box 2)
  - Sheriff's deeds, 1847-1858 (Box 2)
  - Tioga County deeds, 1830-1883 (Box 2, 3)
  - Tioga County mortgages and bonds, 1833-1889 (Box 3)
  - Ogle County, Illinois deeds, 1844-1888 (Box 3)
  - Cortland County mortgages and bonds, 1830-1882 (Box 4)
  - Allegany County deeds, 1842-1861 (Box 4)
  - Broome County deeds, 1852-1884 (Box 4)
  - Chemung County deed, 1865 (Box 4)
  - Onondaga County deed, 1859 (Box 4)
  - Chenango County deeds, 1838-1872 (Box 4)
  - Otsego County deeds, 1872 (Box 4)
  - Pennsylvania land deeds, 1833-1860 (Box 4)
  - Iowa land papers, 1864-1891 (Box 4)
  - Wisconsin land deeds (2), 1858-1861 (Box 4)
  - Genesee County deeds, 1852, 1855, 1858 (Box 4)
  - Cemetery deeds (2), 1838, 1866 (Box 4)
  - Clerk's Office search certificates, Cortland County, 1871, 1880 (Box 4)
  - Letters patent, 1831-1867 (Box 4)
  - Indiana land papers, 1857-1882 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Wonderly contract papers, 1878 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Keeler and Robbins, land contracts, 1863-1889 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Office of Olin, Rives, and Montgomery, 1869-1878 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Mortimer Calkins and John C. Smith papers, 1859-1891 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Nivison papers, 1866-1876 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Ogle County bank-related papers, 1853-1888 (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
  - Bank-related correspondence and legal correspondence, 1860-1891 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Samuel Pulford correspondence, 1860-1891 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Obid Burgess correspondence, 1856-1861 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Lot boundary slips, 1835-1878 and undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous material, Undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Receipts and notes, 1830-1849 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Receipts and notes, 1850's (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Receipts and notes, 1860's (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Receipts and notes, 1860's (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Receipts and notes, 1870's and undated (Box 6, Folder 5-6)
  - Hathaway correspondence, 1864-1881 (Box 6, Folder 7-9)
  - Certificates of land ownership, 1845-1870 (Box 7)
  - Ledger sheets for bonds, cash, loans, promissory notes, mortgages, 1877-1878 (Box 7)
  - Ledger sheets for contracts, sales, and schedules, 1877-1878 (Box 7)
  - Survey bills, 1870-1894 and undated (Box 7)
  - List of leases, 1877-1878 (Box 7)
  - List of purchases, 1877-1878 (Box 7)
  - Rosemary Realty Co. stock certificate book, 1911-1918 (Box 7)
  - Atlantic Utilities Corp. stock certificate book, 1921 (Box 7)
  - Small diary, 1862-1863 (Box 7)
  - Checkbook belonging to F.A. Southworth, 1936-1938 (Box 7)